# Victory Onuoha

FRONT END WEB
DEVELOPER

613-608-9686

Victoryonuoha.com

VictoryOnuoha@cmail.carleton.ca

linkedin.com/in/victorvrita-onuoha

github.com/VictoryOnuoha

Ottawa, Canada

### **PROFILE**

Proven **Web Developer** with a previous background in Neuroscience & Operations and 2+ years of experience in software development.

I transitioned into a career in tech because I wanted a role that encouraged constant growth and had an impact on the global community.

I am passionate about creating engaging user experiences and producing accessible software that is efficient.

## **SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, React js, SQL, Rest API's, Axios, NodeJS, Express JS, SQL, Git, Wireframing, Deployment, Debugging, Testing. Relational Databases, Firebase, Agile Project Management

#### **PROJECTS**

# Full Stack developer | "Victory Folio"

JAN 2022 - FEB 2022, FREELANCE

- Developed mobile-first react web app to help over 1,500 users connect and view my developer portfolio using React.js on the frontend & Node.js on the backend
- Designed and implemented responsive UI Wireframes with Figma, using modern design principles for all screen sizes

## Front End Developer | "BandSite"

JUNE 2022 - JUNE 2022, BRAINSTATION

- Created responsive web apps and optimized site by adding comments feature via an API that can support over 1000+ users
- Enhanced website using Javascript to allow dynamic interaction with comment adding feature

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Web Developer | Freelance

MAR 2021 - Present, CANADA, OTTAWA

 Developed and redesigned over 6 client-specific websites using strong communication and problem solving skills

## Medical Affairs Manager | Appletree Medical Group

NOV 2020 - PRESENT, CANADA, OTTAWA

- Collaborated with over 30+ team members to create workflows for new company initiatives to improve operational efficiency by communicating closely with the executive team
- Restructured training documentations using problem solving skills leading to a 45% increase in productivity

#### Founding Member | Baddies in Tech

Oct 2020 - Present, CANADA, OTTAWA

- As a Founding Member, I implemented the creation of a 20 person organization to facilitate diversity in tech by utilizing leadership and problem solving skills to lead the organization
- Lead the 5+ BiT Content team by the creation of engaging articles using analytical & organizational skills leading to an increase of BiT users by 20% during BiT Website Launch

#### **EDUCATION**

## BrainStation | Diploma Candidate, Web Development

MAY 2022 - AUG 2022, CANADA, OTTAWA

## CodeCademy | Online Certificate, Front End Development

JUNE 2021 - 2022, CANADA, OTTAWA

## Carleton University | Bachelors in Science | Neuroscience

SEP 2013 - 2017, CANADA, OTTAWA

Entrance Scholarship for Academic Excellence